Hi, my name is Dave Andrews.
Today, I'm going to show you how to run a macro in Excel from Access.
Let's begin by opening up Excel.
Let's first create our macro by clicking the view tab.
Go into macros and saying record macro.
We're going to name this macro one just say okay.
All this macro is going to do is type the number one, two, three, four across the top row.
So, let's stop record by clicking this little drop down arrow and saying stop record.
Now, we have our macro created.
So, let's save this as a macro enable workbook.
Click on your office button.
Go to save as.
We're going to save macro enable workbook.
Let's name it book one and just say save.
Now, we need to go into Access by clicking the start button, all programs, Microsoft Office.
Let's open Access.
We need to create a new database by clicking on the office button and saying new.
Let's leave the name as database one and say create.
Here's our new database.
To run that macro from Excel macro from Access, hold down the ALT key on the keyboard.
Press F11.
This brings up the visual basic code editor.
Go to the top.
Say insert.
We're going to say module.
In our code editor, we're going to begin typing in some code.
Now that we have our function created in Access, I'm going to go over it with you real quick.
First thing it does is it creates a variable called Excel and the sign says Excel value.
To the create object function, it launches a new Excel dot application scheme.
It then opens up a Excel database that we give to it which is the path right here that I typed in and then it simply says Excel dot run and then the name of the macro we created which was macro one.
You then could link to this function Excel test within an object in your database.
My name is Dave Andrews and I just showed you how to run an Excel macro from Access.